<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI>
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Letter from <rs key="73859585" type="person">John Ruskin</rs> to <rs key="76205504" type="person">Joan Severn</rs>
					<date when="1867-08-17">August 17 1867</date>
				</title>
				<respStmt>
					<name>Ben Wills-Eve</name>
					<resp>Transcribed</resp>
					<date when="2019-11">November 2019</date>
					<notes></notes>
					<checked>Yes</checked>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<name>Claire McGann</name>
					<resp>Checked transcription</resp>
					<date when="2019-11">November 2019</date>
					<notes>Line 73: the gap is “proper”. Have added in.
Line 104: the gap was “crag”. Have added in. 
Line 117: I changed ‘cloud’ to ‘cross’. 
Line 128: I changed ‘lives’ to ‘lips’. 
Line 155: I changed ‘when’ to ‘whom’. 
Line 177: I changed ‘love’ to ‘form’. (His f’s do sometimes look like that, see ‘flow’ 4 lines down on the next page. 
Line 2014: I changed ‘short’ to ‘that’. 
</notes>
					<checked>Yes</checked>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<listPerson>
					<div>
						<rs key="76205504" type="person">Fitie</rs>
						<rs key="f_crawley" type="person">Crawley</rs>
						<rs key="45147049" type="person">Rosie</rs>
						<rs key="janet_ruskin" type="person">Auntie</rs>
						<rs key="95838041" type="person">Mr Richmond</rs>
						<rs key="54018628" type="person">George</rs>
						<rs key="22146194" type="person">Willie</rs>
						<rs key="61616074" type="person">Julia</rs>
						<rs key="Q479645" type="person">Obadiah</rs>
						<rs key="Q133507" type="person">Elijah</rs>
						<rs key="Q713679" type="person">Timotheus'</rs>
						<rs key="Q9200" type="person">Paul's</rs>
						<rs key="mr_bridges" type="person">Mr Bridges</rs>
						<rs key="73859585" type="person">J Ruskin</rs>
						<rs key="286440449" type="person">Miss Bell</rs>
					</div>
				</listPerson>
				<listPlace>
					<div>
						<rs key="Q1025076" type="place">Keswick</rs>
						<rs key="Q2292191" type="place">Skiddaw</rs>
						<rs key="Q84" type="place">London</rs>
						<rs key="Q5050033" type="place">Castle crag</rs>
						<rs key="Q8025721" type="place">Winnington</rs>
						<rs key="Q5599500" type="place">Langdale</rs>
					</div>
				</listPlace>
				<msDesc>
					<msIdentifier>
						<idno>2003L01532</idno>
						<institution>Lancaster University</institution>
						<repository>Ruskin Library</repository>
						<collection>Ruskin manuscript letters L33</collection>
					</msIdentifier>
					<physDesc>
						<objectDesc form="Letter">
							<supportDesc>
								<extent>
									<measure unit="page" quantity="11"/>
								<dimensions>112mm (w) x 175mm (h)</dimensions>
								</extent>
								<support>Paper</support>
							</supportDesc>
						</objectDesc>
						<accMat type="envelope">
							<supportDesc>
								<extent>
								<dimensions>119mm (w) x 66mm (h)</dimensions>		
								</extent>
								<support>Paper</support>
							</supportDesc>
							<msIdentifier>2003L01532/1</msIdentifier>
							<note>askew's Dungeon Ghill Inn Upper Langdale <gap reason="illegible" unit="words" quantity="1"/></note>
							<note>Portinscale</note>
							<address>
								<addrLine id="a1">
									<rs key="76205504" type="person">Miss Joanna Agnew</rs>
								</addrLine>
								<addrLine id="a2">
									<rs key="Q66813351" type="place">Denmark Hill</rs>
								</addrLine>
								<addrLine id="a3">
									<rs key="Q1394500" type="place">S. London</rs>
								</addrLine>
							</address>
							<stamp id="stamp1" type="postage" position="front">
								<desc>One Penny Postage</desc>
							</stamp>
							<stamp id="stamp2" type="postOffice" position="front">
								<rs key="Q1025076" type="place">Keswick</rs>
								<date when="1867-08-18">AU 18 67</date>
							</stamp>
							<stamp id="stamp3" type="postOffice" position="back">
								<rs key="Q1394500" type="place">London S</rs>
								<date when="1867-08-19">AU 19 67</date>
							</stamp>
						</accMat>
					</physDesc>
				</msDesc>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc><correspDesc>
			<correspAction type="sent">
				<rs key="73859585" type="person">John Ruskin</rs>
				<rs key="Q1025076" type="place">Keswick</rs>
				<date when="1867-08-17"/>
			</correspAction>
			<correspAction type="received">
				<rs key="76205504" type="person">Joan Severn</rs>
				<rs key="Q66813351" type="place">Denmark Hill</rs>
				<date>unknown</date>
			</correspAction>
		</correspDesc></profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>

	
	<text id="ruskin_to_joan_august_17_1867">
	
	    <header>
	        <inventNo>2003L01532</inventNo>
	    </header>
	
	    <body>
	        <div type="text">
	            <pb n="1"/>
	            <opener>
	                <placeName><!-- match letter exactly, delete if unnecessary -->
	                    <rs key="Q1025076" type="place">Keswick</rs>
	                </placeName>
	                <date when="1867-08-17"><!-- match letter exactly, delete if unnecessary -->
	                    <rs type="date">17th August. Evening</rs>
	                </date>
	                <salute>My darling itie <rs key="76205504" type="person">Fitie</rs>,</salute><!-- match letter exactly, delete if
	                unnecessary
	                 -->
	            </opener>
	
	            <p id="p1">
	                <s id="s1">I'm so glad my letters have made you happy</s>
	                <s id="s2">I <hi rend="underline">did</hi> write them carefully, thinking of what my itie 'amie was
	                    feeling, (and I know, pretty well.)</s>
	                <s id="s3">But they're all true - though I chose among true things, what I thought would comfort
	                    itie 'amie the most.</s>
	
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p2">
	                <s id="s4">You would hardly think it, but I'm very uncomfortable myself, with losing count of my
	                    days, - the new 1. 2. 3 seems to go on so dedful slow</s>
	                <s id="s5">I was very miserable  yesterday, I couldn't tell why, but nothing gave me the least
	                    pleasure.</s>
	                <s id="s6">Today, it poured of rain all day long</s>
	                <s id="s7">I had left some stones that I wanted on <rs key="Q2292191" type="place">Skiddaw</rs> top, so I thought I might as well
	                    go and fetch them</s>
	                <s id="s8">I got a rough poney, and a little boy <pb n="2"/> to ride him, between two saddlebags for
	                the stones, and started at 12 oclock, <rs key="f_crawley" type="person">Crawley</rs> &amp; all</s>
	                <s id="s9">- The rain got heavier every foot we mounted - and when we got to the shoulder of flat
	                    moor, under the summmit, the cloud was as thick as <rs key="Q84" type="place">London</rs> fog, and I had to
	                    go by my compass</s>
	                <s id="s10">- I struck the path for the summit without an error of ten feet - after a mile's <add
	                        hand="#JR" place="above">walking</add> straight into the cloud</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p3">
	                <s id="s11">The wind got fierce near the top, and the little boy -( - in a far away way he was like
	                    <rs key="45147049" type="person">Rosie</rs>)- got rather frightened and cold</s>
	                <s id="s12">I left him in as sheltered a place as I could find - with <rs key="f_crawley" type="person">Crawley</rs>
	                    to take care of him - &amp; went on to the top myself</s>
	                <s id="s13">- The rain was crashing among the shingle like a waterspout but the wind, strangely
	                    enough, lulled <del rend="strikethrough">near</del><add hand="#JR" place="above">just at</add>
	                    the summmit - and I stopped a little<pb n="3"/> which then - in my usual way - - I was wet
	                    through of course - all about the limbs, so i could kneel down on the stones without caring</s>
	                <s id="s14">Then I dug up the stone I had hidden</s>
	                <s id="s15">&amp; came back to <rs key="f_crawley" type="person">Crawley</rs> and the boy - and found some more of
	                    my nests and filled my saddlebags, and braced up the little fellow between them, and cheered him
	                up, <add hand="#JR" place="above">too and I'm going to give him a suit of clothes tomorrow,</add> and
	                    set off downwards</s>
	                <s id="s16">I saw him safe enough across the moor into the regular horse path, and then left him to
	                    <rs key="f_crawley" type="person">Crawley</rs> and came down myself by a short cut</s>
	                <s id="s17">It rained worse at the top than it had done at the bottom - and when I got down again -
	                it rained at the bottom worst of all!</s>
	                <s id="s18">I got home by 1/2 past four - dined at 5 and had nearly a pint of sherry - <add
	                        hand="#JR" place="above">your boy a basin of hot soup, rich &amp; fine</add> now I've had
	                    tea too, and am very jolly</s>
	                <s id="s19">What beasts we are!</s>
	                <s id="s20">Yesterday <add hand="#JR" place="above">doing nothing, &amp; drinking little,</add> in
	                    spite of all self-examination &amp; lecturing and proper thinking - I was utterly
	                    wretched - today, I've had a wetting and a pint of sherry, &amp; I'm all right<pb n="4"/></s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p4">
	                <s id="s14">Sunday morning</s>
	                <s id="s15">18th Aug</s>
	                <s id="s16">It's very odd, i always feel so much better after these wet days than after dry ones</s>
	                <s id="s17">I'm as fresh as a daisy - this morning</s>
	                <s id="s18">- Not much inclined ot go to church, though - - but I shall - and see what is said to me-</s>
	                <s id="s19">For you and <rs key="janet_ruskin" type="person">Auntie</rs> have, I doubt not, been triumphing over me in
	                    a way which you haven't the least business to do.</s>
	                <s id="s20">For, first - I suppose you read the things which happened to me last Sunday as if they
	                    meant that I was always to go to church -</s>
	                <s id="s21">But <hi rend="underline">I</hi> read them, at present - quite differently - I read them "If
	                    you
	                    <hi rend="underline">intend</hi> to go to church, you are not to fail in that proposed duty,
	                    because you are anxious about your letters; but you are quite right in questioning whether it is
	                    good for you to go to church at all."</s>
	                <s id="s22">And this <hi rend="underline">is</hi> at present a very principal question with me.</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p5">
	                <s id="s23">Alas - I notice in one of your late letters some notion that I am coming to think the
	                    Bible the "word of God" - because I use it - out of <rs key="45147049" type="person">Rosie's</rs> book - for
	                    daily teaching,<pb n="5"/> (N . B,) verse for today Ps. 47. 7.)</s>
	                <s id="s24">- But I never was farther from thinking - and never can be nearer to, thinking, anything
	                of the sort</s>
	                <s id="s25">Nothing <del rend="strikethrough">I</del> could ever persuade me that God writes vulgar
	                    Greek</s>
	                <s id="s26">If an angel all over peacocks' feathers were to appear in the bit of blue sky now over
	                    <rs key="Q5050033" type="place">Castle crag</rs> - and to write
	                    on it in flat letters - "God writes vulgar Greek" -
	                I should say -"<hi rend="underline">you</hi> are the Devil, peacocks' feathers and all</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p6">
	                <s id="s27">If there is any divine truth at all in the mixed collection of books which we call a
	                    Bible, that truth is, that the Word of God comes <hi rend="underline">directly</hi> to different
	                people in different ways; and may do so to you or to me, today, and has nothing whatever to do with
	                    printed books, and that on the contrary, people may read that same collection of printed books
	                    all day long all their lives, and never, through all their lives hear <add hand="#JR"
	                                                                                               place="above">or
	                    receive</add> one syllable of "God's word"</s>
	                <s id="s28">That cross in the sky was the word of God to you - as far as I can at present suppose
	                    anything, in such matters - at all events it may have been - and in the clouds of<pb n="6"/> 19th
	                    July - and the calm sky of last Monday morning - there may have been the Word of God to me.
	                </s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p7">
	                <s id="s29">And continually, by and through the words of <hi rend="underline">any</hi> book <add
	                        hand="#JR" place="above">in</add> which we reverently expect divine teaching, <del
	                        rend="strikethrough">in</del>, the word of God may come to us: and because I love <rs key="45147049" type="person">Rosie</rs> so, I <hi rend="underline">think</hi> God does teach me, every
	                    morning, by her lips, through her book, at all events, I know I get good by believing this</s>
	                <s id="s30">But one must above all things be cautious of allowing one's vanity to meddle in the
	                    matter - or of expecting a perpetual Divine help and interference</s>
	                <s id="s31">Most peoples religion is so inwoven with their vanity that <del
	                        rend="strikethrough">it</del><add hand="#JR" place="above">their religion</add> becomes the
	                    worst thing about them.</s>
	                <s id="s32">There was a trial in the papers only the other day about a woman who had her head turned
	                by having 500,000 pounds left her - she said she was the Holy Ghost, and whenever she went into
	                    church, said -"If only the people knew who I am!"</s>
	            </p>
	            <pb n="7"/>
	            <p id="p8">
	                <s id="s33">{My wee, busy, useful pussie, cuzzies own wee pussie - please as far as you can arrange
	                    at once the following matters for me</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p9">
	                <s id="s34">I. I shall not be able to go with <rs key="95838041" type="person">Mr Richmond</rs> to see pictures - I
	                am resolved to see and do nothing whatever that I can help that I should <hi rend="underline">like
	                    </hi> to <hi rend="underline">+</hi> and I should mightily have liked that</s>
	                <s id="s35">+ I mean of serious things, of course I shall like to take 'amies to see heathers, and
	                    the second piece of business is</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p10">
	                <s id="s36">II. Please accept with heartiest gratitude the kind offer to get us archbishops
	                    permission to run in heather - but that <rs key="54018628" type="person">George</rs> may know what he's about -
	                &amp; whom he's letting into consecrated ground - read him the end of this letter (no - don't, but
	                    tell him the sense of it.)</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p11">
	                <s id="s37">III. I shall be delighted to see <rs key="22146194" type="person">Willie</rs> whenever he can come, or
	                    likes to, (<rs key="61616074" type="person">Julia</rs> would get my letter yesterday morning.)}</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p12">
	                <s id="s38">Well - I've been to church, and have made<pb n="8"/> up my mind that I shall continue to
	                go - - First, you see, the psalms for the day seemed to go straight at what <del
	                            rend="strikethrough">I</del> was troubling me in remembering the days (90, 12th and 15th)
	                    and the 91st had <hi rend="underline">many</hi> things in it for me and the 92nd, 4th <del
	                            rend="strikethrough">is</del> was always an old standard verse of mine</s>
	                <s id="s39">Well - then, came the <rs key="Q479645" type="person">Obadiah</rs> &amp; <rs key="Q133507" type="person">Elijah</rs>
	                    chapters, which fell in with much that I had been thinking about the fight I should have with the
	                    clergymen - showing how priests of Baal really <hi rend="underline">believe their own</hi>
	                    mission, and how to be<add hand="#JR" place="above">quoted and</add> killed out of it - <hi
	                            rend="underline">can't</hi> be put to shame in their own hearts - I got a great deal too
	                    - out of all the chapter - the rainy bits - especially</s>
	                <s id="s40">Then in the second lesson, the bit about <rs key="Q713679" type="person">Timotheus'</rs> father being
	                    Greek, &amp; <rs key="Q9200" type="person">Paul's</rs> giving way to the useless matter of form - was very
	                    useful to me, and other things - too many to speak of</s>
	                <s id="s41">I got dreamy during the Litany - looking at a man who was saying it all quite straight
	                    off, and yawning, like to split himself, meanwhile</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p13">
	                <s id="s42">Then, they sang -(and you know the music's lovely), the 23rd Psalm - "the Lord himself,
	                    the mighty Lord", &amp;c which was nice for me, only I had nearly<pb n="9"/> gone into a <add
	                            hand="#JR" place="above">violent</add> fit of -quite out - laughing by unluckily
	                    thinking when they came to "cool shades, and where reflecting waters flow"- of the top of <rs key="Q2292191" type="place">Skiddaw</rs> the day before!</s>
	                <s id="s43">I had to bite my lips dedful hard - and if anybody was looking they must have been
	                    shocked past all wonder</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <p id="p14">
	                <s id="s44">Well - there wasn't much more till the sermon - which was upon the Bible's being a
	                    Revelation - and it <add hand="#JR" place="above">(the sermon)</add> was so abominably bad that
	                    it came to me as a distinct farther assertion of the Bible's being no such thing - and the more
	                    I looked at the man, the more his <add hand="#JR" place="above">face</add> seemed to me like one
	                of the ugly faces under the cathedral gutters, spouting out dirty water, - pure once, but defiled by
	                    <hi rend="underline">them</hi> and the dirt <del rend="strikethrough">of</del><add
	                            hand="#JR" place="above">inside</add> the leaden gutters they stick on - and I felt how
	                    completely here was a priest of Baal, - who wanted extinction as soon as might be.</s>
	                <s id="s45">And yet the man quite believed in himself, and in all he was saying - or trying to say</s>
	                <s id="s46">And then I came<pb n="10"/> away - on the whole much helped and taught, and satisfied
	                    that from that <rs key="45147049" type="person">Rosie's</rs> rose day, I was meant to go to church again.</s>
	                <s id="s47">So I'll take you to <rs key="mr_bridges" type="person">Mr Bridges</rs>
	                    <del rend="strikethrough">on</del> this day week, God willing, and him</s>
	            </p>
	
	            <closer>
	                <salute>ever your own loving cuzzie</salute><!-- optional -
	                delete if
	                unnecessary -->
	                <signed><!-- optional - delete if unnecessary -->
	                    <rs key="73859585" type="person">J Ruskin</rs>
	                </signed>
	             </closer>
	
	            <postscript>
	                <p id="p15">
	                    <s id="s48">It's a lovely day and I'm going to have some dinner now, and then row about among the lovely
	                        rocks of the lake shore, till sunset</s>
	                </p>
	
	                <p id="p16">
	                    <s id="s49"><rs key="286440449" type="person">Miss Bell</rs> is sending me some money from <rs key="Q8025721" type="place">Winnington</rs> - I told her to register the half notes to <hi
	                            rend="underline">you</hi> - as I don't know if they would come safe in time to <rs key="Q5599500" type="place">Langdale</rs> - where I'm going back on Tuesday</s>
	                    <s id="s50">When you get them, write to say you have - &amp; the other halves will come</s>
	                </p>
	            </postscript>
	
	        </div>
	    </body>
	</text>
</TEI>
