It O
was O
fine O
yesterday O
, O
and O
I O
took O
a O
light O
carriage O
, O
and O
drove O
with O
Downes O

                 O
up O
Borrowdale B-LOC
, O
and O
round O
under O
Honister O
- O
crag B-LOC
, O
to O

                     O
Buttermere B-LOC
, O
and O
played O
a O
little O
while O
at O
the O
edge O
of O
the O
same O
stream O
which O

                     O
I O
got O
scolded O
for O
dabbling O
in O
till O
I O
was O
too O
late O
for O
dinner O
, O
when O
I O
was O
a O
boy O

The O
dinner O
was O
a O
very O
bad O
one O
, O
I O
remember O
; O
and O
I O
used O
it O
afterwards O
in O
my O
speech O
at O
Oxford B-LOC
, O
on O
Education O
of O
the O
Lower O
Classes O
, O
- O
because O
the O

                     O
girl O
at O
Buttermere B-LOC
had O
a O
piano O
in O
the O
parlour O
, O
and O
nothing O
in O
the O
kitchen O

We O
came O
home O
through O
the O
vale O
of O
Newlands B-LOC

Both O
passes O
were O
higher O
& O
grander O
than O
I O
expected O
; O
but O
driving O
a O
long O
way O

                     O
through O
moors O
is O
duller O
than O
walking O
, O
for O
at O
least O
in O
walking O
, O
one O
has O
to O
look O
where O
one O
is O

                     O
going O
, O
and O
that O
is O
amusing O
. O

I O
've O
just O
got O
your O
most O
nice O
letter O
of O
yesterday O
. O

I O
understand O
it O
all O
perfectly O
. O

I O
'm O
very O
glad O
you O
like O
the O
" O
Selections O
" O
and O
about O
Mr O
Simon's B-PER
garden O

