The O
weather O
is O
really O
very O
endurable O
now O
, O
and O
to O
be O
commended O
, O
for O
Cumberland B-LOC
: O
it O
was O
shady O
and O
clear O
yesterday O
, O
without O
rain O
. O
and O
I O
did O
what O
I O
had O
long O
had O
it O
in O
mind O
to O
do O
, O
- O
went O
straight O
up O
the O
steep O
front O
of O
Saddleback B-LOC
by O
the O
central O
ridge O
to O
the O
summit O
. O

It O
is O
the O
finest O
thing O
I O
've O
yet O
seen O
, O
there O
being O
several O
bits O
of O
real O
Crag O
- O
work O
, O
and O
a O
fine O
view O
at O
the O
top O
over O
the O
great O
plains O
of O
Penrith B-LOC
on O
one O
side O
and O
the O
Cumberland O
hills B-LOC
, O
as O
a O
chain O
, O
on O
the O
other O
. O

Fine O
fresh O
wind O
blowing O
and O
plenty O
of O
crows B-FAU
. O

Do O
you O
remember O
poor O
papa O
's O
favourite O
story O
about O
the O
Quakers O
whom O
the O
crows B-FAU
ate O
on O
Saddleback B-LOC
. O

There O
were O
some O
of O
the O
biggest O
and O
hoarsest O
- O
voiced O
ones O
about O
the O
cliff O
that O
I O
've O
ever O
k O
had O
sympathetic O
croaks O
from- O
and O
one O
on O
the O
top O
, O
or O
near O
it O
, O
so O
big O
, O
that O
Downes B-PER
and O
Crawley B-PER
having O
Austrian O
tendences O
in O
politics O
, O
took O
it O
for O
a O
" O
black O
eagle B-FAU
" O
Downes B-PER
went O
up O
capitally O
, O
though O
I O
could O
n't O
get O
him O
down O
again O
, O
because O
he O
would O
stop O
to O
gather O
ferns B-FLO
. O

However O
we O
did O
it O
all O
and O
came O
down O
to O
Threlkeld B-LOC
, O
- O
of O
the O
Bridal O
of O
Triermain O
, O

" O
The O
King O
his O
way O
pursued O
By O
Lonely O
Threlkeld's B-LOC
waste O
& O
wood O
" O
in O
good O
time O
for O
me O
to O
dress O
and O
for O
a O
wonder O
, O
go O
out O
to O
dinner O
, O
with O
Acland's B-PER
friends O
the O
Butlers B-PER
, O
-chiefly O
to O
meet O
a O
young O
Scotchman- O
whom O
I O
will O
tell O
you O
about O
in O
Joanna B-PER
's O
letter O
as O
this O
is O
enough O
for O
you O
to O
read O
to O
day O

