It O
is O
a O
fine O
morning O
and O
Joanna B-PER
is O
very O
well O
and O
in O
high O
spirits O
about O
Percy's B-PER
birthday O
, O
and O
we O
are O
going O
in O
		 O
the O
afternoon O
to O
see O
Glenluce B-LOC
, O
as O
you O
wished O
. O

( O
thanks O
for O
nice O
and O
beautifully O
written O
letter O
received O
yesterday O
) O
. O

We O
drove O
yesterday O
to O
Garlieston B-LOC
, O
and O
called O
on O
three O
old O
ladies O
, O
" O
Miss O
McLanes" B-PER
- O
living O
with O
their O
brother O
in O
		 O
a O
pretty O
house O
by O
the O
seaside O
- O
it O
was O
all O
so O
intensely O
like O
a O
scene O
in O
Sir O
Walter O
Scott B-PER
. O

They O
were O
real O
ladies O
, O
and O
it O
was O
very O
sweet O
and O
nice O
. O

I O
had O
a O
quiet O
evening O
of O
rest O
, O
Joanna B-PER
playing O
and O
singing O
very O
nicely O
. O

I O
am O
much O
pleased O
to O
see O
her O
in O
such O
bright O
health O

I O
have O
enclosed O
an O
envelope O
for O
Keswick B-LOC
as O
I O
am O
not O
quite O
sure O
if O
your O
Saturday O
's O
letter O
would O
arrive O
on O
Sunday O
here O
. O

But O
it O
is O
safe O
at O
the O
old O
Royal O
Oak B-LOC
, O
where O
I O
am O
going O
for O
old O
times O
' O
sake O
, O
and O
if O
I O
find O
it O
now O
altered O
and O
uncomfortable O
I O
shall O
go O
		 O
on O
to O
Wast O
- O
water B-LOC
on O
some O
other O
place O
where O
I O
can O
have O
pure O
air O
and O
climbing O
, O
for O
I O
mean O
to O
make O
the O
most O
I O
can O
of O
the O
time O
I O
take O
		 O
from O
you O
. O

