I O
have O
your O
nice O
letter O
saying O
you O
were O
so O
much O
interested O
by O
the O
account O
of O
the O
apprentice O
of O
the O
river O
: O
I O
will O
get O
the O
Times O
and O
look O
at O
it O

I O
see O
no O
papers O
here O
, O
on O
purpose O
. O

They O
disturb O
my O
peace O
of O
mind O
mightily O
- O
and O
I O
'm O
trying O
to O
think O
of O
nothing O
at O
all O
- O
but O
Rose B-PER
- O
who O
is O
everywhere O
all O
day O
long O
, O
		 O
quietly O
. O

I O
found O
a O
very O
interesting O
scene O
yesterday O
in O
a O
dingle O
quite O
hitherto O
unknown O
to O
me O
, O
on O
the O
left O
hand O
side O
of O
the O
lake O
, O
and O
am O
going O
over O
there O
again O
to O
- O
day O
		 O
- O

It O
was O
pouring O
rain O
yesterday O
, O
and O
I O
had O
leap O
three O
streams O
, O
and O
wade O
one O
, O
where O
usually O
there O
are O
only O
little O
, O
trickling O
brooklets O
, O
and O
the O
Derwent B-LOC
, O
in O
which O
a O
doggie O
no O
bigger O
than O
Wisie O
would O
hardly O
have O
found O
a O
pool O
where O
he O
could O
swim O
, O
a O
week O
ago O
, O
is O
now O
a O
steady O
, O
grand O
, O
eddying O
		 O
torrent O
like O
a O
main O
branch O
of O
the O
Tay B-LOC
. O

- O
There O
Cumberland B-LOC
and O
Scotch B-LOC
streams O
, O
at O
their O
strongest O
- O
are O
however O
never O
like O
Swiss B-LOC
		 O
ones O
, O
- O
for O
great O
reasons O
, O
they O
never O
flow O
down O
steep O
slopes O

- O
though O
often O
with O
no O
more O
water O
actually O
in O
the O
bed O
at O
one O
time O
than O
in O
the O
Cumberland B-LOC
torrent O
- O
for O
going O
six O
times O
the O
pace O
, O
it O
		 O
can O
deliver O
six O
times O
the O
quantity O
of O
water O
in O
the O
same O
time O
, O
without O
being O
any O
deeper O
. O

I O
hope O
you O
will O
have O
Joanna B-PER
with O
you O
on O
Thursday O
. O

I O
shall O
be O
so O
much O
more O
comfortable O
. O

