I O
was O
calling O
to O
- O
day O
on O
the O
Mr O
and O
Mrs. O
Butler B-PER
of O
Oxford B-LOC
, O
who O
lost O
their O
little O
daughter O
by O
her O
falling O
		 O
downstairs O
( O
over O
the O
bannisters O
- O
she O
is O
a O
very O
sweet O
and O
nice O
person O
. O

I O
imagine O
it O
washe O
who O
must O
have O
taught O
the O
child O
to O
climb O
over O
the O
bannisters O
. O

They O
are O
staying O
at O
the O
house O
on O
the O
island O
, O
Mr. O
Marshalls B-PER
, O
which O
is O
a O
very O
fine O
piece O
of O
like O
gardening O
and O
building O
. O

Mr O
Marshall B-PER
himself O
very O
like O
John O
Lewis B-PER
but O
seems O
nicer O
. O

Afterwards O
, O
as O
it O
was O
raining O
and O
blowing O
hard O
, O
I O
could'nt O
row O
, O
so O
I O
climbing O
Wallacrag B-LOC
and O
found O
that O
I O
'm O
getting O
my O
		 O
limbs O
again O
gradually O
. O

And O
that O
's O
all O
I O
can O
write O
to O
- O
day O
, O
for O
I O
was O
kept O
later O
by O
the O
rain O
, O
in O
reaching O
home O
. O

I O
've O
written O
a O
line O
to O
Kate O
on O
her O
marriage O
- O
It O
's O
very O
hard O
having O
to O
congratulate O
everybody O
and O
never O
being O
married O
myself O
. O

