It O
is O
really O
a O
settled O
fine O
evening O
at O
last O
, O
of O
which O
I O
am O
glad O
, O
because O
of O
Downes B-PER
- O
for O
I O
see O
it O
is O
generally O
more O
or O
less O
the O
same O
weather O
everywhere O
. O

I O
am O
going O
to O
take O
a O
little O
carriage O
half O
way O
to O
Penrith B-LOC
& O
under O
Saddleback B-LOC
& O
look O
at O
some O
rocks O
I O
want O
to O
see O
there O
and O
pull O
Downes B-PER
out O
of O
the O
train O
when O
it O
stops O
at O
the O
Troutbeck O
station B-LOC
- O
( O
not O
the O
Troutbeck B-LOC
you O
and O
I O
used O
to O
go O
to O
from O
Bowness B-LOC
) O
and O
to O
take O
him O
down O
the O
old O
mail O
coach O
road O
into O
Keswick B-LOC
- O
if O
the O
evening O
is O
fine O
, O
it O
will O
be O
quite O
lovely O
. O

I O
am O
very O
well O
, O
though O
still O
rather O
sulky O
- O
Love O
to O
Tom B-PER
. O

