Their O
posts O
are O
so O
awkward O
here O
that O
I O
am O
pretty O
sure O
to O
miss O
the O
one O
at O
Carlisle B-LOC
, O
so O
this O
is O
to O
enclose O
your O
to O
- O
morrow O
's O
envelope O
and O
		 O
to O
say O
, O
I O
called O
on O
Miss O
McAdam B-PER
Mrs. O
Young's B-PER
niece O
yesterday O
, O
and O
was O
much O
pleased O
by O
her O
gentle O
face O
and O
beautiful O
		 O
manner O
. O

The O
Scottish O
real O
ladies O
of O
the O
middle O
classes O
of O
England B-LOC
, O
or O
perhaps O
more O
accurately O
, O
the O
Scottish O
aristocracy O
is O
a O
much O
larger O
body O
		 O
than O
the O
English O
, O
though O
the O
greater O
part O
of O
it O
untitles O
. O

The O
evergreens B-FLO
in O
her O
garden O
were O
planted O
by O
Mrs. O
Youngs B-PER
and O
are O
now O
beautiful O
- O
not O
having O
		 O
suffered O
at O
all O
by O
last O
spring O
's O
frost O
. O

I O
called O
also O
in O
my O
old O
uncle O
Tweeddale's B-PER
house O
, O
on O
Lane O
- O
I O
am O
pleased O
with O
Arbuthnot B-PER
who O
is O
to O
marry O
Kate B-LOC
: O
and O
very O
much O
pleased O
indeed O
with O
his O
family O
, O
especially O
his O
sister O
and O
her O
husband O
. O

I O
hear O
excellent O
accounts O
of O
the O
one O
who O
has O
engaged O
Mary B-PER
. O

The O
Procurator O
Fiscal O
of O
Dumfries B-LOC
must O
be O
a O
very O
good O
position O
. O

Mary B-PER
herself O
is O
a O
far O
nicer O
and O
more O
intelligent O
girl O
than O
I O
supposed O
. O

Kate B-PER
is O
very O
good O
too O
, O
and O
much O
improved O
happiness O
. O

I O
have O
been O
quite O
comfortable O
without O
Crawley B-PER
, O
but O
must O
go O
now O
to O
Keswick B-LOC
to O
get O
put O
to O
rights O
in O
portmanteau B-LOC

