I O
discovered O
too O
late O
yesterday O
that O
there O
was O
no O
post O
on O
Sunday O
, O
so O
I O
could O
only O
send O
telegram O
. O

You O
will O
get O
this O
, O
and O
I O
hope O
another O
from O
Carlisle B-LOC
, O
on O
Tuesday O
morning O
. O

I O
went O
to O
Glen O
Luce B-LOC
on O
friday O
afternoon O
- O
it O
is O
much O
prettier O
than O
Wigtown B-LOC
, O
the O
ruins O
of O
the O
abbey O
are O
still O
		 O
very O
beautiful O
- O
but O
the O
manse O
, O
alas O
, O
had O
been O
pulled O
down O
, O
and O
rebuilt O
in O
the O
vulgar O
Scotch O
way O
. O

The O
river O
and O
valley O
, O
and O
banks O
of O
wood O
sloping O
down O
, O
with O
wild O
rose B-FLO
and O
wild O
pinks B-FLO
, O
were O
all O
as O
		 O
lovely O
as O
could O
be O
. O

But O
the O
provincial O
towns O
are O
more O
and O
more O
reduced O
and O
absorbed O
by O
the O
capital O
ones O
, O
and O
every O
country O
town O
I O
have O
passed O
through O
in O
Cumberland B-LOC
, O
Yorkshire B-LOC
, O
and O
Scotland B-LOC
, O
has O
the O
same O
aspect O
of O
deep O
melancholy O
and O
ruin O
. O

I O
am O
writing O
carelessly O
this O
morning O
for O
I O
am O
a O
little O
despondent O
at O
the O
sight O
of O
these O
old O
places O
, O
and O
I O
'm O
sorry O
to O
leave O
Joanna B-PER
and O
		 O
her O
sisters O
, O
for O
I O
know O
that O
my O
being O
here O
must O
be O
a O
great O
pleasure O
to O
them O
, O
- O
but O
this O
place O
is O
too O
far O
from O
either O
hills O
or O
sea O
to O
be O
any O
good O
to O
me O
, O
so O
		 O
I O
must O
go O
back O
to O
Cumberland B-LOC
. O

I O
hope O
to O
send O
a O
more O
cheerful O
letter O
with O
this O
. O

I O
have O
yours O
, O
I O
fear O
a O
little O
nervious O
about O
Crawley's B-PER
home O
coming O
. O

