I O
've O
been O
writing O
a O
long O
letter O
to O
Joanna B-PER
- O
thinking O
every O
now O
and O

                 O
then O
between O
sentences O
and O
it O
has O
taken O
so O
mu O
much O
more O
time O
than O
I O

                     O
intended O
. O

- O
and O
I O
can O
only O
say O
, O
to O
day O
in O
this O
, O
that O
I O
'm O
very O
thankful O
to O
hear O
of O
that O
peace O
which O

                     O
came O
over O
you O
, O
and O
that O
I O
remain O
myself O
remain O
very O
peaceful O
and O
happy O
, O
and O
will O
write O
more O

                     O
tomorrow O
( O
though O
I O
shall O
not O
get O
your O
letter O
at O
Keswick B-LOC
in O
time O
to O
answer O

                     O
it O
) O
- O
I O
go O
back O
to O
Keswick B-LOC
because O
I O
left O
it O
before O
I O
had O
done O
, O
to O
show O
Downes B-PER
Windermere B-LOC
- O
if O
it O
is O
fine O
tomorrow O

I O
shall O
go O
up O
Helvellyn B-LOC
again O
on O
the O
way O
back O
. O

It O
was O
too O
cold O
when O
I O
was O
with O
Downes B-PER
to O
see O
all O
I O

                     O
wanted O
at O
the O
top O
. O

