I O
hope O
this O
will O
reach O
you O
to O
- O
morrow O
morning O
: O
we O
take O
extra O
penny O
's O
worth O
of O
precaution O
that O
it O
may O
. O

- O
I O
got O
to O
Newton O
- O
Stewart B-LOC
quite O
comfortably O
yesterday O
and O
found O
Joan B-PER
and O
Kate B-PER
waiting O
, O
		 O
and O
the O
country O
all O
the O
way O
from O
Dumfries B-LOC
was O
much O
more O
beautiful O
than O
I O
expected O
, O
and O
Newton O
Stewart B-LOC
also O
, O
and O
this O
little O
		 O
house O
is O
as O
comfortable O
as O
can O
be O
, O
and O
my O
room O
immensely O
nice O
- O
and O
it O
is O
really O
very O
good O
for O
me O
to O
be O
for O
a O
little O
while O
without O
Crawley B-PER
. O

I O
was O
getting O
so O
dreamy O
, O
I O
could O
not O
in O
the O
least O
take O
care O
of O
myself O

- O
I O
mean O
to O
return O
to O
Keswick B-LOC
on O
Monday O
, O
- O
please O
tell O
any O
of O
the O
servants O
to O
tell O
Crawley B-PER
if O
he O
picks O
up O
his O
		 O
things O
at O
Carlisle B-LOC
and O
comes O
to O
the O
Derwentwater B-LOC
here O
on O
Monday O
evening O
it O
will O
be O
all O
right O
. O

I O
am O
quite O
well O
and O
getting O
stronger O
. O

- O
I O
must O
be O
short O
to O
- O
day O
to O
catch O
post O
. O

Joanna's B-PER
& O
everybody O
's O
love O
. O

Mary O
is O
much O
improved O
and O
Kate O
's O
expression O
very O
sweet O

