Your O
writing O
is O
better O
and O
better O
every O
day O
: O
I O
would O
not O
send O
you O
so O
many O
envelopes O
, O
much O

                 O
as O
I O
like O
to O
have O
the O
letters O
, O
but O
that O
I O
see O
this O
, O
and O
that O
the O
little O
effort O
of O
writing O
them O
is O

                     O
really O
good O
for O
you O
. O

I O
looked O
directly O
at O
the O
third O
chapter O
of O
Job B-PER
. O

I O
have O
not O
for O
a O
long O
while O
; O
and O
it O
is O
strange O
to O
see O
what O
false O
despair O
a O
good O
man O
may O
be O

                 O
brought O
to O
. O

I O
have O
just O
heard O
of O
the O
destruction O
of O
the O
church O
of O

                     O
St O
John O
& O
Paul O
& O
at O

                     O
Venice O
, O
and O
of O
Titian's B-PER
best O
picture O
but O
one O
, O
the O
Peter O
Martyr O
, O
therein O
, O

                     O
with O
perfect O
equanimity O
. O

Nevertheless O
there O
is O
under O
that O
, O
the O
undercurrent O
of O
the O
quiet O
and O
continual O

                     O
despair O
about O
such O
things O
which O
has O
long O
possessed O
me O
. O

If O
my O
own O
Turner's B-PER
St I-PER
Gothard B-LOC
were O
destroyed O

                     O
- O
you O
would O
find O
me O
take O
it O
just O
the O
same O
way O
. O

There O
is O
a O
good O
deal O
, O
I O
hope O
, O
in O
Joanna's B-PER
letter O
, O
which O
will O
amuse O
you O
, O
and O

                     O
I O
must O
write O
no O
more O
to O
- O
day O

The O
idea O
of O
a O
Pipe O
like O
Robin O
Hood's B-PER
is O

                             O
capital O
. O

I O
will O
begin O
to O
learn O
to O
whistle O
on O
one O
directly O
. O

It O
is O
, O
quite O
seriously O
, O
a O
right O
& O
useful O
idea O
. O

Full O
address O
on O
Envelope O
- O
being O
the O
last O
, O
I O
hope O
, O
here O
, O
this O
year O
. O

