I O
fear O
you O
will O
be O
disappointed O
when O
you O
find O
this O
thick O
letter O
only O
a O
heap O
of O
various O
ones O
, O
but O
I O

                 O
think O
most O
of O
them O
will O
interest O
you O
. O

See O
message O
in O
George B-PER
's O
about O
sausages O
and O
wine O
. O

I O
have O
told O
Miss O
Hill B-PER
she O
may O
write O
to O
mama O
on O
the O
birthday O
Keep O
Constance's B-PER
for O
me O
. O

She O
complains O
much O
of O
you O
not O
writing O
to O
her O
. O

I O
thought O
it O
was O
all O
the O
other O
way O
. O

I O
am O
just O
leaving O
for O
Langdale B-LOC
in O
a O
grievously O
wet O
day O
. O

I O
wrote O
to O
Tom O
Richmond B-PER
last O
night O
, O
giving O
up O
all O
thoughts O
of O
the O

                 O
Windermere B-LOC
house O
- O
as O
far O
as O
I O
am O
concerned O
. O

This O
climate O
is O
well O
enough O
for O
walking O
& O
eating O
- O
but O
not O
for O
living O
in O
. O

Did O
I O
tell O
you O
the O
saying O
of O
a O
little O
girl O
, O
communicated O
to O
me O
the O
other O
day O
by O
a O

                     O
clergyman O
's O
wife O
- O
" O
It O
's O
so O
difficult O
to O
know O
where O
God O
ends O
, O
and O
the O
Devil O
begins O
" O

It O
is O
long O
since O
I O
heard O
something O
so O
comprehensive O
of O
all O
problems O
of O
human O
life O
- O
( O
and O

                 O
weather O
! O
- O
How O
it O
does O
rain O
this O
morning O
! O
) O

Nothing O
to O
answer O
I O
see O
- O
Thank O
mama O
for O
Lily's B-PER
letter O

