<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI>
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Letter from <rs key="73859585" type="person">John Ruskin</rs> to <rs key="47637407" type="person">Margaret Cock Ruskin</rs>
					<date when="1867-07-30">July 30 1867</date>
				</title>
				<respStmt>
					<name>Claire McGann</name>
					<resp>Transcribed</resp>
					<date when="2019-11">November 2019</date>
					<notes></notes>
					<checked>Yes</checked>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<name>Ben Wills-Eve</name>
					<resp>Checked transcription</resp>
					<date when="2019-11">November 2019</date>
					<notes></notes>
					<checked>Yes</checked>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<listPerson>
					<div>
						<rs key="47637407" type="person">Mother</rs>
						<rs key="8821113" type="person">Downes</rs>
						<rs key="76205504" type="person">Joanna</rs>
						<rs key="73859585" type="person">J Ruskin</rs>
					</div>
				</listPerson>
				<listPlace>
					<div>
						<rs key="Q4925984" type="place">Saddleback</rs>
						<rs key="Q23360" type="place">Cumberland</rs>
					</div>
				</listPlace>
				<msDesc>
					<msIdentifier>
						<idno>1996L00323</idno>
						<institution>Lancaster University</institution>
						<repository>Ruskin Library</repository>
						<collection>Ruskin manuscript letters B6</collection>
					</msIdentifier>
					<physDesc>
						<objectDesc form="Letter">
							<supportDesc>
								<extent>
									<measure unit="page" quantity="3"/>
								<dimensions>112mm (w) x 175mm (h)</dimensions>
								</extent>
								<support>Paper</support>
							</supportDesc>
						</objectDesc>
						<accMat type="envelope">
							none
						</accMat>
					</physDesc>
				</msDesc>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc><correspDesc>
			<correspAction type="sent">
				<rs key="73859585" type="person">John Ruskin</rs>
				<rs key="" type="place"></rs>
				<date when="1867-07-30"/>
			</correspAction>
			<correspAction type="received">
				<rs key="47637407" type="person">Margaret Ruskin</rs>
				<rs key="" type="place"></rs>
				<date>unknown</date>
			</correspAction>
		</correspDesc></profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>

	
	<text id="ruskin_to_mother_july_30_1867">
	    
	    <header>
	        <inventNo>1996L00323</inventNo>
	    </header>
	
	    <body>
	        <div type="text">
	            <pb n="1"/>           
	            <opener>
	
	                <date when="1867-07-30"><!-- match letter exactly, delete if unnecessary -->
	                    <rs type="date">Tuesday 30th July</rs>
	                </date>
	                <salute>My dearest <rs key="47637407" type="person">Mother</rs>.</salute><!-- match letter exactly, delete if unnecessary -->
	            </opener>
	
	            <p id="p1">
	                <s id="s1"><rs key="8821113" type="person">Downes</rs> arrived yesterday quite comfortably and in fine weather It is not bad this morning, and I hope to take him for a walk up <rs key="Q4925984" type="place">Saddleback</rs>, which after all is the finest to my mind, of all the <rs key="Q23360" type="place">Cumberland</rs> hills - though that is not saying much, for they are much lower in effect, in proportion to their real height, than I had expected- The beauty of the country is in its quiet roadside bits, and rusticity of cottage life and shepherd labour. - its mountains are sorrowfully melted away from my old dreams of them.</s>
	                </p>
	                             
	            <p id="p2">
	                <s id="s2">I have your nice line of yesterday- I am so thankful to know that <pb n="2"/>you can still read nicely.. it is only now &amp; then, when you are tired, that I see any failure in the writing.</s>
	            </p>
	            
	             <p id="p3">
	                <s id="s3">I think that arrangement about not reading <rs key="76205504" type="person">Joanna</rs>'s letters to <hi rend="underline">me</hi> and only mine to her will be quite right.</s>
	                <s id="s4">It will leave her quite at ease and unrestrained.</s>
	            </p>
	            
	            <closer>
	                <salute>Ever my dearest <rs key="47637407" type="person">Mother</rs> Your most <expan>aff<ex cert="high">ectionat</ex>e</expan> Son,</salute><!-- optional - delete if unnecessary -->
	                <signed><!-- optional - delete if unnecessary -->
	                    <rs key="73859585" type="person">J Ruskin</rs>
	                </signed>
	             </closer>
	
	        </div>
	
	    </body>
	
	</text> 
</TEI>
